VINAY TANWER

Email: vtanwer3933@gmail.com Phone: +91 7708805027 (M) +91 129 2213921 (R) Address: House No. 1131-J, Sector-2, Faridabad, Haryana - 121004

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with 2 years of experience in interpreting and analysing data for driven business solutions. Proficient knowledge
of statistics, mathematics and analytics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective
analysis of data.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Degree	Institute/School	CGPA/ %	Year
B.Tech. (Electrical and Electronics Engineering)	National Institute of Technology, Tiruchirappalli	8.2/10.0	2011-15
AISSCE (Class XII th - CBSE)	Grand Columbus International School, Faridabad	86.8%	2010-11
AISSE (Class X th - CBSE)	Kendriya Vidyalaya, Palwal	80.6%	2008-09

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ATS Services Pvt. Ltd., Faridabad Data Analyst, December 2017 - Present

- Create Machine learning models to generate customer scorecards of Insurance portfolios using tools like Python, R etc.
- Data wrangling, manipulation, massaging, extraction and strategy automation on tools like Python, Oracle, PL/SQL.
- Data Cleaning, Pre-processing and automation on VBA Macros.
- Provide strategic insights for business development and cost optimization.
- Time series forecasting and Revenue projection.
- Customer profiling, clustering and segmentation.
- Creation of Excel dashboards for reporting and process tracking.

<u>Titan Company Limited, Precision Engineering Division, Hosur</u> Senior Engineer, July 2015- April 2017

Design and Program Automatic Assembly Machines.

Certification

Big Data with Hadoop and Spark

CloudxLab, December 2018 - Present

- Basics of Linux/Unix
- Understanding of Hadoop Ecosystem viz., HDFS, Yarn, Zookeeper, Hive, HBase, Map Reduce etc.
- Scala Programming
- Spark programming and exposure to spark libraries like MLLib, GraphX, Spark SQL etc.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Data Analytics: Proficient in using analytical tools like Python (numpy, pandas, sklearn, tensorflow, keras, matplotlib etc.), R, SQL, Advanced Excel, VBA, Tableau and SAS.
- Machine Learning Algorithms: Linear and Logistic Regression, Time Series analysis, SVM, K-Means Clustering, KNN, PCA,
 Decision Trees, Random Forest, Naïve Bayes, Ensemble Methods(Bagging and Boosting), Artificial Neural Networks (DNN,
 CNN, RNN, Autoencoders) etc.

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Date of Birth: 31st October, 1993
- Interests: Football, Dance, Music